VINCENT GINES

SUMMARY

Expert Lead Web Developer specializing in front-end development. Experienced with all stages of development cycle for dynamic web projects. Well-versed in HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery and Windows/Mac. Strong background in management and leadership. Graduating in Spring 2021 with education and experience in web development. Highly poised and dedicated with talent in design principles and programming languages. Excellent eye for visual aesthetics paired with insight into data and backend functionality.

SKILLS

- Javascript
- Bulma, Bootstrap, Materialize
- Problem-Solving
- Team-Player

EXPERIENCE

THIRD MANAGER | 04/2013 to 05/2015 Public Storage - San Francisco, CA

- Collaborated with staff to maximize customer satisfaction, streamline procedures and improve bottom-line profitability.
- Conducted inventory counts by assessing current state of inventory integrity against target accuracy levels and tracking variances.
- Trained employees on additional job positions to maintain coverage of roles at all times.
- Facilitated month-end journal entries, account reconciliation and invoicing.
- Drove financial performance of assigned areas by verifying achieved sales and profit goals and implementing plans to correct deficiencies.
- Collaborated with visual merchandising team to develop strategies to drive profitability.
- Greeted and encouraged feedback from customers to implement in-store operational changes.
- Completed thorough opening, closing and shift change functions to maintain operational standards each day.

VISUAL MERCHANDISER | 11/2008 to 12/2012 Forever 21 - Chino Hills, CA

- Supervised up to 30 employees on merchandising team.
- Restructured merchandising strategy to promote high value and products.
- Managed visual displays for Forever 21 to drive exposure and increase revenue.
- Created retail displays to highlight particular products and drive sales according to corporate strategy.
- Promoted new product releases and limited edition items to drive sales.
- Enhanced store and display appearance utilizing seasonal promotions and trends to drive strategy.
- Presented updated floor plans and design strategy to store management.
- Configured and arranged up-to-date advertising and marketing displays, creatively placed merchandise on counters or tables to promote visibility and sales.

STORE MANAGER | 06/2003 to 11/2008 Vans - Brea. CA

- Boosted sales by 180% by cultivating customer rapport and delivering superior customer service.
- Opened and closed store by processing daily paperwork, balancing register drawers, producing staffing schedules and preparing deposits.

- Worked closely with District Manager to formulate and build store brand and strategy.
- Generated repeat business by responding to customer concerns with friendly and knowledgeable service.
- Developed and optimized store schedules to meet expected coverage demands and maintain optimal service levels.
- Interviewed, hired, supervised and trained 30 employees and instituted mentoring program to develop skills, leadership and employee excellence.
- Met budget targets by controlling expenses and eliminating wasteful behaviors.
- Trained employees on store security, monetary procedures and customer service expectations.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

University Of California, Berkeley Extension - Berkeley, CA Certificate

Web Development, Expected in 03/2021

University Of California Riverside - Riverside, CA Some College (No Degree)

Business Economics

Bear Creek High School - Stockton, CA High School Diploma 06/1999